Imam Hossain

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub | WhatsApp

Location: Dhaka,Bangladesh Email: imamhossain98@gmail.com | Mobile: 01775984338

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled web developer with over **1** years of experience in **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **and Nodejs**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **React**, **React Native and NextJs** and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks : React.js, React Native, NextJs, Express, Node.js, Redux

Libraries : Material UI, Bootstrap 5, Redux, React Router, Framer Motion, Headless UI

Databases : MongoDB

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Vercel, NetlifyApp

SKILLS

- · Graphics Design
- MS Office
- Management
- Communication
- Leadership
- · Letter Writing.

EXPERIENCE

Cheif Executive

Muldhara Express Ltd.

Apr 2021 – Present Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Recording financial transactions. Assisting with financial reporting.
- Accounts Receivable and Accounts.
- Payable Management.
- Payroll Management.
- E-mail corespondance.
- Letter Writing.

Self Enthusiastic Learner

Web Developer

Aug 2021 – Nov 2022 Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Worked with Popular React and NextJS frameworks to develop robust and scalable backends
- Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend to ensure smooth operation of the applications
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from databases
- Improved website performance and speed through optimization techniques by 55%

EDUCATION

A.K High School SSC	Dhaka,Bangladesh Jan 2010 – Jun 13
Donia University College <i>HSC</i>	Dhaka,Bangladesh Jul 2013 – Aug 2015
Kabi Nazrul Govt. College <i>BBA in Management</i>	Dhaka,Bangladesh Jan 2016 – Dec 2021
Programming Hero Full Stack web Development Course	Dhaka,Bangladesh Aug 2021 – Dec 2021

Project 1

Next.js, HTML, TailwindCSS Git

Source Code

- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, Headless UI
- Optimized website for speed and user experience
- Utilized **responsive design** to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Deployed on Vercel via GitHub Actions

Project 2

NextJS, HTML, TailwindCSS Git

Source Code

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with Node.js
- Exposed POST, GET, PATCH and DELETE HTTP methods using Express

CERTIFICATIONS

• Certified Web Developer by the Programming Hero

REFERENCE

Syed Md Jahangir *Managing Director*

Muldhara Express Ltd.

9/A, Dhanmondi, Dhaka, Bangladesh +8801775984338